Ahmed Ahmed

Software Engineer

I'm a Logical and results-driven Software Engineer dedicated to building and optimizing user-focused solutions for customers with various business objectives. Judicious and creative when crafting effective solutions and platforms to propel competitive advantage and revenue growth. Technically proficient and analytical problem solver with calm and focused demeanor. Experienced Software Engineer with Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.



★ trybemark@gmail.com

Q Lagos, Nigeria

github.com/dudox

2347017723208

in linkedin.com/in/ahmed-ahmed-3a366016b

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Manager YouROK Corp.

06/2021 - Present

Califonia, USA

YouROK is a prevention focused solution developed to address the adolescent mental health crisis by building emotional resiliency using evidence-informed practices

Achievements/Tasks

- Managed a team of technical web developers
- Oversaw technical interviews for new recruits
- Implemented Microservice for the entire company products. ie enterprise platform, parents platform and kbro application
- Used GraphQL to map data and created an API Gateway to improve load balancing

Technical Lead ConsultantReal Art Daily Production

05/2021 - Present

Califonia, USA

Real Art Daily (RAD) Productions, a video production company based in Los Angeles, is a diverse company with employees representing a wide range of sexualities, gender identities, races, cultures, and nationalities.

Achievements/Tasks

- Create documentation and approach to solutions for the team and company
- Advise on cost effective decisions and system effective approaches
- Developed an intranet website using react, nodejs, express and mongodb to support company's daily objectives

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Collaboration and teamwork

Problem solving and creativity

Leadership

Time Managements

riority Managements

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Backend

Nodejs, PHP, Express.js, JSON, GraphQL (Apollo Federation)

Frontend

HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, React Components

Database

MySQLi, MongoDB, Sequelize, Amazon RDS, PostGreSQL, REDIS

Frameworks

BootStrap, React.js, Laravel, Angular.js, jQuery

Development Stacks

MEAN, MERN, LAMP

DevOps

Pipeline, Continuous Delivery and Continuous Integration, Docker, Deployments, Version control, Testing and Cloud Quality tools

Cloud Server

AWS, Azure, DigitalOcean

Tools

Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Visual Studio Code, Github, Slack

Architectures

Microservices

3rd Party API

Payment Gateways, SMS Integrations, USSD Integrations, Social Media Bots

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Web Developer Real Art Daily Production

03/2021 - 05/2021

Califonia, USA

Real Art Daily (RAD) Productions, a video production company based in Los Angeles, is a diverse company with employees representing a wide range of sexualities, gender identities, races, cultures, and nationalities.

Achievements/Tasks

- Migrated several websites from bluehost to digitalocean droplets
- Improve wordpress website performance and load time
- Coordinated with my team to implement lazy loading, revamp and improve website readability, reliability
- Created tutorials on Linux Commands to support deployments of websites for the team/company

Backend Engineer YouROK Corp.

03/2021 - 06/2021

Califonia, USA

YouROK is a prevention focused solution developed to address the adolescent mental health crisis by building emotional resiliency using evidence-informed practices.

Achievements/Tasks

- Refactored back-end frameworks and fixed existing issues to support mobile development team RestFul API Requests using Drupal (PHP)
- Met Product Requirements and setup security measure to protect users data
- Managed DevOps Operations on Amazon Web Services and created pipelines to handle auto deployments to test, stage and production phases.
- Gradually Transitioned the current architecture from a monolithic to a standalone microservices architecture using docker
- Refactored Web Products from Wordpress to React and translated/developed frontends to the UI/UX Requirements.
- Managed a team of front-end developers, created API's documentation and resolved conflicts of coordinated team contributions.
- Advised on cost effective and performative approaches to improve product delivery to customers and also for foundational work framework to improve security and reduce down time affected by bugs

Contact: Patrina Mack

Senior Software Engineer

Smart Sahara

10/2020 - 01/2021

Lagos, Nigeria

As a brand, we never stop innovating the future. We have impacted Africa positively in key areas of huge economic impact with vibrant smart solutions and supports for nearly a decade.

Achievements/Tasks

- Managed a team of front developers
- Built a mobile online marketplace with easy user experience.
- Worked with Mern Stack, Digitalocean, Firebase to handle push notifications for web view platforms
- Integrated Systems.

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science Kwara State University

10/2016 - 06/2019

Lagos, Nigeria

Courses

 Adaptive Agro-monitoring System with the use of Augmented Reality

PERSONAL PROJECTS

FERMA Road Alert Software (06/2019 - 08/2019)

- Software built with PHP, Laravel, RestFul API and Bootstrap
- Implemented 3rd party SMS and USSD to support and coordinate reports of bad roads
- Created Road Analytics and Data Management across Nigeria in order to support over 100 local governments and over 150 federal roads in Nigeria

Adaptive Agro Monitoring System (01/2019 - Present)

- Developed circuit design
- Implemented embedded systems around Arduino Uno and connected part to circuitry
- System can gather data from soil, current weather, detect animals around using signature and alarm farmers
- System can map data of different weather locations and farming data based on success rates and implement same data skewed to weather condition of other locations

Covid 19 Report System (02/2020 - 06/2020)

- USSD Interaction with system using survey tactics to gather data
- Run data analytics of reports based on specific locations
- Give recommendation of severity of illness and automatically report to the NCDC

ACHIEVEMENTS

LiFT Scholarship Receipeints (07/2020 - 01/2021)

The Linux Foundation training (LiFT) program provides advanced open source training to existing and aspiring IT professionals.

Tech Person of the year (01/2018 - 12/2019)

Tech person of the year is awarded by the Faculty of Computer science at the University of Kwara State Nigeria.

Global Entrepreneurship Week Winner (12/2019 - 12/2019)

Global Entrepreneurship Week is present in over 100 countries where young entrepreneurs showcases idea's and develop practical systems to support their ideas.

INTERESTS

Artificial Intelligence

Climate Change

Equality

REFERENCES

Patrina Mack (CEO) "YouROK Corp"

Contact: patrina@yourokapps.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Mayapro1 Limited

01/2019 - 11/2019

Lagos, Nigeria

A leading Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) firm licensed by Nigerian Communications Commission (NCC) for Value Added Services (VAS) & Content Services Using Shortcodes (SNC)

Achievements/Tasks

- Revamp and refactoring of existing products
- Worked with RestFul API's, Ajax calls and JSON
- Developed projects with PHP Frameworks (Laravel)
- Built SMS, USSD and Webhooks to support payments integration
- Developed Governments Systems to the COVID-19 Pendemic
- Developed Government Systems for road safety precautions.
- Developed Marketing Campaign Support Web Solutions

Web Developer McBeki

06/2018 - 12/2018

Lagos, Nigeria

Mc Beki is a digital branding company with broad expertise in UI/UX, Graphics Design, Web Development and Audio Visualization

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed Company's Websites
- Translated UI/UX Design to meet brands objectives using HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Developed anti-theft mobile recovery website
- Incorporated websites in 8 African countries i.e Nigeria, Uganda, Zambia, Ghana, Kenya etc

Web DeveloperHezedge Consulting

04/2018 - 11/2018

Lagos, Nigeria

HezEdge Consulting is a digital solution company with a team of young professionals with expertise in all areas of digital production (digital media, digital publishing, digital media marketing, business intelligence solutions, web and software/mobile app development).

Achievements/Tasks

- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Conducted functional testing over course of web development lifecycle.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Developed functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Campus Ambassador

Ingressive

01/2018 - 01/2019

Kwara, Nigeria

Ingressive launched a community called Ingressive Campus Ambassadors in a bid to give back to the African tech ecosystem by focusing on Students with a passion for tech

Tasks/Achievements

- Organized Bootcamp in Web Development, UI/UX, Graphics Design and Mobile App Development.
- Responsible for the role as a Web Development Instructor

Contact: Ingressive

LANGUAGES

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Yoruba

Native or Bilingual Proficiency